MEGAN ELIZABETH DAY

FRONT-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

MEGANEDAY7@GMAIL.COM

MEGANEDAY.COM

SKILLS

- HTML5 & CSS3
- SASS
- JavaScript
- React.js
- Ruby on Rails
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Slack, Zoom, Microsoft 360, JIRA, and other project management softwares
- Salesforce B2C Commerce Cloud
- Web Content Development
- Technical Blog Writing
- Visual Studio Code
- Figma and Zeplin wireframe tools
- Responsive Design

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE BOOTCAMP

FLATIRON SCHOOL APRIL-AUG 2021

BACHELOR OF ARTS WRITING FOR PERFORMANCE, SUMMA CUM LAUDE

COLUMBIA COLLEGE CHICAGO SEPT 2014 - MAY 2018



SUMMARY

Full stack software engineer with 2 years of experience in web development. Possesses a keen eye for detail and a passion for developing innovative and user-friendly web experiences. Seeking to employ creative solutions, empathy, and design expertise to improve user experiences across the web.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

REFORMATION

post-production for Salesforce ecommerce site

- Designed and engineered solutions to frontend styling and performance bugs on theformation.com ecommerce site
- Utilized Sass, JavaScript, XML templates, and Salesforce Business Manager to complete all assigned tickets to customer's satisfaction

IMPASTA SYNDROME

an app for storing and sorting through gluten-free recipes

- Utilized JSON web tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user data
- Designed a fun and unique in-browser experience using Vanilla CSS.
- Engineered input forms that enable users to dynamically create lists of ingredients and instructions for recipes.

GROOMSMART

an app for managing your pets' grooming appointments

- Curated a branded, professional user experience using Vanilla CSS.
- Designed backend server on Ruby on Rails framework with ActiveRecord responsible for returning and persisting data.

EXPERIENCE

SALESFORCE ECOMMERCE FRONTEND DEVELOPER BORN GROUP - REMOTE | 2021 - PRESENT

- Participated in a 3 month full-stack training program to learn
- Salesforce B2C Ecommerce for Developers

 Completed all assigned tickets in a timely manner utilizing
- knowledge of frontend design patterns and frameworks.
- Provided QA on all assigned tickets and completed code reviews and QA for team's development solutions.
- Debugged frontend issues for post-production clients, which increased client retention by 20%.
- Participated in daily scrum calls and weekly sprint planning meetings.
- Successfully supervised and collaborated across a 15-person team in preparation and execution of weekly development sprints.

CHILDCARE PROVIDER

PRIVATE FAMILIES - CHICAGO, IL | 2018-2021

- Lovingly provided hands-on solutions and care to demanding clients between the ages of 6 months 9 years.
- Carefully followed parents' expectations and requirements with agility; troubleshot care plans accordingly.
- Fostered safety and assessed quality of environment for a child with special needs.
- Regularly exercised resilience, attention to detail, and de-escalation.